<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<GateDocument>
<!-- The document's features-->

<GateDocumentFeatures>
</GateDocumentFeatures>
<!-- The document content area with serialized nodes -->

<TextWithNodes> 
In the frame of the Helmholtz-Russian Joint Research Groups (HRJRG) ‘Structural aspects of biocompatible ferrofluids by scattering methods: stabilization, properties control and applications’ GKSS Research Center Geesthacht, Department of Structural Research on Macromolecules, offers 
 1 PhD POSITION (three years).
 
HRJRGs bring together research capacities from Russian Research Centres and/or Universities and Helmholtz Centres, thus creating a centre of excellence with international standing and attractiveness to researchers in a key area of research. Here the Joint Institute for Nuclear Research (JINR, Dubna, Russia), Russian Research Centre “Kurchatov Institute” (Moscow, Russia),GKSS Research Center (Geesthacht, Germany) and the University Hospital Hamburg Eppendorf (Hamburg, Germany) form this network. Central part of the project is the development of magnetic nanoparticles which can be incorporated into brain cancer cells for therapeutical use. 
 Project description: The PhD-project will be focussed on the evaluation of cell interactions (mainly glioblastoma) with magnetic nanoparticles. This includes the determination of particle uptake, viability and migration properties of the cells. The influence of an external magnetic field on several microbiological parameters will be studied. A close collaboration with the physicists and chemists who will develop and optimize the magnetic nanoparticles and the medical scientists of the University Hospital is a prerequisite for the successful implementation of this PhD thesis. 
 Requirements: Completed undergraduate studies (master or diploma certificate) in the area of chemistry, biology, biochemistry or biophysics. Good knowledge in cell and molecular biology as well as interest in experimental cross-disciplinary work are vital. Language (fluent English and preferably also German or Russian) and computational skills are indispensable. 
 
This HRJRG offers first class scientific and complementary training to coach 'life science' experts who learn to work across disciplines. We therefore expect high motivation to work on an interdisciplinary field, extraordinary communication skills and the readiness to work for visits or short secondments at different host institutions.
 
Please send you application (with CV, copy of certificates and a summary of university courses and your personal skills) not later than <Node id="2397"/>15.11.2007<Node id="2407"/> to Dr. R. Willumeit: <Node id="2429"/>regine.willumeit@gkss.de<Node id="2453"/> (only email applications will be considered).
 </TextWithNodes>
<!-- The default annotation set -->

<AnnotationSet>
</AnnotationSet>

<!-- Named annotation set -->

<AnnotationSet Name="Key">
<Annotation Id="0" Type="Электронная_почта" StartNode="2429" EndNode="2453">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="1" Type="Дата" StartNode="2397" EndNode="2407">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">месяц</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">11</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
</AnnotationSet>

</GateDocument>
