<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<GateDocument>
<!-- The document's features-->

<GateDocumentFeatures>
</GateDocumentFeatures>
<!-- The document content area with serialized nodes -->

<TextWithNodes><Node id="0"/>
The premises are suited for up to 1000 participants, with up to four parallel sessions taking place in four (also parallel) conference rooms. The exhibition is arranged in close proximity to the conference rooms, as are the lunch and coffee.

The event spans three full days from Tuesday 23rd to Thursday 25th of September 2008. It's organized in parallel with Biotech Forum <Node id="376"/>(http://www.biotechforum.org/)<Node id="406"/> and ScanLab (<Node id="420"/>http://www.scanlab.nu/).<Node id="444"/>

The conference concentrates on three application areas: Sustainable solutions for energy and environment, Nanotechnology-enabled ICT and Nanobiotechnology and nanomedicine. Additionally all these topics are discussed from the standpoint of Business Development and Tech Transfer.
Sustainable solutions for energy and environment: Hydrogen technology Solar cells Energy efficient materials Nano catalysts Fuel cells Nanotechnology-enabled ICT: NanoPhotonics NanoSensors Quantum information and communication Nanomaterials for ICT Nanoelectronics Nanobiotechnology and nanomedicine: Biomaterials Biosensors Diagnostics Drug delivery Food Nanotechnology Business Development: Global trends, Safe development of nanotechnologies, International cooperation, Industrial perspective, Entrepreneurs and VCs Tech Transfer, workshops: Tech transfer sessions Targeted workshops  Flemming Besenbacher, iNANO, University of Aarhus Thomas Bjørnholm, Nano-Science Center, Copenhagen University Peer Tidemand-Petersson, Advanced Technology Foundation, Denmark Hanne Haarup Thomsen, Danish Agency for Science, Technology and Innovation Birthe Schouby, Danish Agency for Science, Technology and Innovation Anders Overgaard Bjarklev, Technical University of Denmark Pekka Koponen, Event Director, Spinverse Laura Juvonen, Event Coordinator, Spinverse 
The exhibition is arranged in the central exhibition hall of Bella Center in the immediate vicinity of the conference rooms. The exhibition stand sales begin in October 2007. If you have any questions regarding the exhibition, please contact Laura Juvonen.

You can also browse the list of exhibitors in the past Nanotech Northern Europe exhibitions:
 Nanotechnology in Northern Europe 2005 exhibitors: <Node id="2182"/>http://www.nanotech.net/…hibitors.htm<Node id="2219"/> Nanotechnology in Northern Europe 2006 exhibitors: <Node id="2271"/>http://www.nanotech.net/…hibitors.htm<Node id="2308"/> Nanotech Northern Europe 2007 exhibitors: <Node id="2351"/>http://www.nanotech.net/…tor_List.htm<Node id="2388"/> 
The registration and call for papers for NTNE 2008 will open by December 2007. Please subscribe to the Nanotech Conferences Newsletter to be informed when the registration opens and to receive the call for papers directly to your e-mail inbox.

The lead organiser of the event is Spinverse, a consulting and seed capital company focusing on the commercialisation of emerging technologies. Spinverse introduced Nanotech Northern Europe conference and exhibition in 2005. You can view presentations from the past events here, or browse freely their websites:
 Nanotechnology in Northern Europe 2005: <Node id="2988"/>http://www.nanotech.net/ntne2005/<Node id="3021"/> Nanotechnology in Northern Europe 2006: <Node id="3062"/>http://www.nanotech.net/ntne2006/<Node id="3095"/> Nanotech Northern Europe 2007: <Node id="3127"/>http://www.nanotech.net/ntne2007/<Node id="3160"/>  Pekka Koponen (Event Director) Tel. +358 40 545 008 Send e-mail to Pekka: <Node id="3236"/>pekka.koponen(at)spinverse.com<Node id="3266"/>  Katriina Forsström (Conference Coordinator) Tel. +358 40 565 1325 Send e-mail to Katriina: <Node id="3359"/>katriina.forsstrom(at)spinverse.com<Node id="3394"/>  Laura Juvonen (Event Coordinator) Tel. +358 40 589 6263 Send e-mail to Laura: <Node id="3474"/>laura.juvonen(at)spinverse.com<Node id="3504"/>  Tom Crawley (Conference Coordinator) Tel. +358 50 463 7149 Send e-mail to Tom: <Node id="3585"/>tom.crawley(at)spinverse.com<Node id="3613"/> More information about Nanotech Northern Europe 2008: <Node id="3668"/>http://www.nanotech.net<Node id="3691"/>/…ormation.php</TextWithNodes>
<!-- The default annotation set -->

<AnnotationSet>
</AnnotationSet>

<!-- Named annotation set -->

<AnnotationSet Name="Key">
<Annotation Id="0" Type="связи_с_другими_организациями" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="1" Type="связи_с_другими_организациями" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="2" Type="Url" StartNode="420" EndNode="444">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="3" Type="Url" StartNode="2988" EndNode="3021">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="4" Type="Url" StartNode="3585" EndNode="3613">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="5" Type="Url" StartNode="376" EndNode="406">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="6" Type="Url" StartNode="2351" EndNode="2388">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="7" Type="Url" StartNode="2182" EndNode="2219">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="8" Type="связи_с_другими_организациями" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="9" Type="Url" StartNode="3127" EndNode="3160">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="10" Type="Url" StartNode="3359" EndNode="3394">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="11" Type="Url" StartNode="3062" EndNode="3095">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="12" Type="Url" StartNode="3236" EndNode="3266">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="13" Type="Url" StartNode="2271" EndNode="2308">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="14" Type="Url" StartNode="3668" EndNode="3691">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="15" Type="Url" StartNode="3474" EndNode="3504">
</Annotation>
</AnnotationSet>

</GateDocument>
