<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<GateDocument>
<!-- The document's features-->

<GateDocumentFeatures>
</GateDocumentFeatures>
<!-- The document content area with serialized nodes -->

<TextWithNodes><Node id="0"/>16-ый Международный симпозиум «<Node id="31"/>Наноструктуры<Node id="44"/>: Физика и технология»Только что узнал, что, оказывается, во Владивостоке, в Институте автоматики и процессов управления (ИАПУ) ДВО РАН уже не <Node id="187"/>первый год<Node id="197"/> проводится этот престижнейший международный симпозиум.16th International Symposium «NANOSTRUCTURES: Physics and Technology»
(Vladivostok, Russia 14–19, July 2008)
ANNOUNCEMENT &amp; CALL FOR PAPERSOrganizers Institute for Automation and Control Processes of Far Eastern Branch of the Russian Academy of Sciences Scientific Engineering Center for Microelectronics at the Ioffe Institute St Petersburg Physics and Technology Centre for Research and Education of the RAS Ioffe Physico-Technical Institute in association with Institutions of the Russian Academy of Sciences Division of Physical Sciences of the Russian Academy of Sciences Far Eastern Branch of the Russian Academy of Sciences St Petersburg Scientific Center of the Russian Academy of Sciences Ministry of Education and Science of the Russian Federation Co-Chairs Zh. ALFEROV (Russia), Nobel Prize laureate L. ESAKI (Japan), Nobel Prize laureate Sponsors Russian Academy of Sciences Russian Foundation for Basic Research AIXTRON AG, Germany Administration of Primorsky Region of the Russian Federation Spectra Physics Ltd. «Euro-Asia» Found, Vladivostok, Russia Рабочий язык – английский. Поэтому все объявления и представляемые материалы тоже на английском языке.
К сожалению, как мы видим, сроки представления материалов на симпозиум <Node id="1492"/>этого года<Node id="1502"/> уже прошли…
Main Topics
The symposium programme will cover different aspects of semiconductor nanostructure research. We are seeking for contributions in the following, non-exhaustive list of topics:
 Technology of Nanostructures: Growth, Self-Organization and Nanopatterning Atomic-scale Characterization of Nanostructures Electrical and Optical Properties of Nanostructures (including Spin-related Phenomena, Many Particle Effects, Infrared and THz Phenomena) Nanostructure Device Applications in Opto-Ultrafast Electronics and Computing Nanophotonics, Microcavity and Photonic Crystals: Properties, Characterization and Applications Emerging Materials in Nanostrucutures (including Wide-bandgap Semiconductors, Oxides, Ferromagnetics, Carbon-based, Polymer and Biomaterials) Nanostructures and Life Sciences Nanomechanical Systems and their Applications 
..........
Important Dates Deadline for submission of pdf-files February 20, 2008 Notification of abstract acceptance April 10, 2008 Deadline for submission of accepted abstracts April 17, 2008 Deadline for personal data submission April 17, 2008 Deadline for advanced payment June 16, 2008 Deadline for payment refund June 30, 2008 CorrespondenceOrganizing Committee N.G.Galkin, Institute for Automation and Control Processes FEB RAS 5, Radio Street, Vladivostok 690041, Russia – <Node id="2842"/>galkin@iacp.dvo.ru<Node id="2860"/> K.V. Ignatovich, Institute for Automation and Control Processes FEB RAS 5, Radio Street, Vladivostok 690041, Russia – <Node id="2979"/>ignat@iacp.dvo.ru<Node id="2996"/> 
Skype : ru_silicon GMT +10
Passport and Visa Osokina T.M., Institute for Automation and Control Processes FEB RAS 5, Radio Street, Vladivostok 690041, Russia – <Node id="3158"/>osokina@iacp.dvo.ru<Node id="3177"/> Accommodation, Payment S.B. Nikiforova, Institute for Automation and Control Processes FEB RAS 5, Radio Street, Vladivostok 690041, Russia – <Node id="3319"/>nikifor@iacp.dvo.ru<Node id="3338"/> Social Programme S.S. Voznesensky and A. Dyshljuk, Institute for Automation and Control Processes FEB RAS 5, Radio Street, Vladivostok 690041, Russia – <Node id="3491"/>vss@iacp.dvo.ru<Node id="3506"/> Proceedings Elena Solovyova, St Petersburg Physics and Technology Centre for Research and Education of the RAS 8, bld. 3 Khlopina, St Petersburg 195220, Russia – <Node id="3669"/>lena.solovyova@mail.ioffe.ru<Node id="3697"/> Proceedings printingA.V. Zotov , Institute for Automation and Control Processes FEB RAS 5, Radio Street, Vladivostok 690041, Russia – <Node id="3832"/>zotov@iacp.dvo.ruhttp://ntc.dvo.ru/nano2008/http://ntc.dvo.ru<Node id="3893"/>/…008/1st.htmlНу, как видим, очень солидное и интереснейшее мероприятие, которое наверняка заинтересует многих исследователей во всём мире… Желаем им успехов!</TextWithNodes>
<!-- The default annotation set -->

<AnnotationSet>
</AnnotationSet>

<!-- Named annotation set -->

<AnnotationSet Name="Key">
<Annotation Id="0" Type="связанные_термины" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="1" Type="Наноструктура" StartNode="31" EndNode="44">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">связанные_организации</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">null</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="2" Type="связанные_организации" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="3" Type="связанные_организации" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="4" Type="связи_с_другими_организациями" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="5" Type="связанные_организации" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="6" Type="связанные_организации" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="7" Type="связанные_организации" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="8" Type="Электронная_почта" StartNode="2842" EndNode="2860">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="9" Type="Электронная_почта" StartNode="3158" EndNode="3177">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="10" Type="связанные_термины" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="11" Type="связанные_организации" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="12" Type="Электронная_почта" StartNode="3832" EndNode="3893">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="13" Type="Электронная_почта" StartNode="3319" EndNode="3338">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="14" Type="связанные_термины" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="15" Type="Электронная_почта" StartNode="3491" EndNode="3506">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="17" Type="связи_с_другими_организациями" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="16" Type="связанные_термины" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="19" Type="связанные_термины" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="18" Type="связанные_организации" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="21" Type="связанные_термины" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="20" Type="связанные_термины" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="23" Type="Период_времени" StartNode="1492" EndNode="1502">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="22" Type="связанные_организации" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="25" Type="связанные_термины" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="24" Type="Электронная_почта" StartNode="2979" EndNode="2996">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="27" Type="связанные_организации" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="26" Type="Период_времени" StartNode="187" EndNode="197">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="29" Type="связанные_термины" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="28" Type="Электронная_почта" StartNode="3669" EndNode="3697">
</Annotation>
</AnnotationSet>

</GateDocument>
