<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<GateDocument>
<!-- The document's features-->

<GateDocumentFeatures>
</GateDocumentFeatures>
<!-- The document content area with serialized nodes -->

<TextWithNodes><Node id="0"/>Н а п о м и н а н и е
Завтра в Cанкт-Петербурге открывается…
Вторая международная конференция по нанобиотехнологиям в Санкт-ПетербургеСанкт-Петербургский Гос. <Node id="159"/>Политехнич<Node id="169"/>. УниверситетВремя проведения: <Node id="200"/>16—18 июня 2008 г.<Node id="218"/>
Место проведения: Cанкт-Петербург

Общие затраты на проведение конференции предполагаются в объеме <Node id="318"/>1200 тыс.рублей<Node id="333"/>.
Подробнее см. <Node id="349"/>здесь:http://www.nanonewsnet.ru/…t-peterburgeThe<Node id="397"/> Second Saint-Petersburg International Conference on NanoBiotechnologies
Russia Saint-Petersburg (June, 16–18 2008)
ЛенэкспоThe aim of this event is to set the discussion between biologists, physicists, computer scientists and engineers, traditionally divided groups, and bridge the gap between materials science and life science.Organizers
• Ministry of Education and Science of Russian Federation

• Federal Agency on Science and Innovations

• M.V. Lomonosov Moscow State University

• Saint-Petersburg State Polytechnical University

• Saint-Petersburg State University

• Saint-Petersburg State University of Technology and Design

• Scientific Journal “Nanotechnologies in Russia”

• Austrian-Russian Working Group on Innovation Cooperation in the Industry and Science

• National Scientific Council “Fullerenes and Atomic Clusters”

• National Documentation Center (Greece)

• National Information Center on Science and Innovations (Russia)

• Applied Nanobiotechnology JSC

• Center for Advanced Studies of Saint-Petersburg State Polytechnical University

• Exhibition Center “Lenexpo”
CONFERENCE COMMITTEESConference Chairs
Mikhail Alfimov, Academician of RAS, Director of the Photochemistry Center of RAS, Russia

Mikhail Fiodorov, Corresponding Member of RAS, Rector of the Saint-Petersburg State Polytechnical University, Russia

Viktor Sadovnichij, Academician of RAS, Rector of the M.V.Lomonosov Moscow State University, Russia
International Advisory Committee
Istvan Hargittai, Budapest University of Technology and Economics, Hungaria

Ralf Hofestädt, Faculty of Technology, Bielefeld University, Germany

Sergey Inge-Vechtomov, Saint-Petersburg State University; Vavilov Institute of General Genetics (Saint-Petesburg Branch) of RAS, Russia

Mikhail Kirpichnikov, M.V.Lomonosov Moscow State University, Russia

Sergey Kozyrev, Co-Chair, Center for Advanced Studies, Saint-Petersburg State Polytechnical University, Russia

Sven Lidin, Stockholm University, Sweden

Ron Lifshitz, Tel Aviv University, Israel

Achim Müller, Faculty of Chemistry, Bielefeld University, Germany

Michael O'Keeffe, Arizona State University, USA

Eiji Osawa, NanoCarbon Research Institute Co., Ltd., Japan

John Reinitz, Co-Chair, Stony Brook University, USA

Uwe Sleytr, Center for Nanobiotechnology, University of Natural Resources and Applied Life Sciences (BOKU), Austria

Vladimir Torchilin, Center for Pharmaceutical Biotechnology and Nanomedicine, Northeastern University, USA

Victor Ustinov, Saint-Petersburg Physics and Technology Centre for Reserch and Education, RAS, Russia
National Program Committee
Husein J. Chechenov, Co-Chair, Chairman of The Council of the Federation Committee for Education and Science

Mikhail Kirpichnikov, Co-Chair, M.V.Lomonosov Moscow State University Leonid Balashevich, S.N. Fyodorov IRTC “Eye Microsurgery”, St. Petersburg Branch

Boris Basin, Plasmofilter Ltd.

Yury Chizhov, St.Petersburg State University

Alexander Samsonov, Ioffe Physico-Technical Institute of RAS

Maria Samsonova, Center for Advanced Studies, Saint-Petersburg State Polytechnical University

Konstantin Shaitan, Bioengineering Department, Biological Faculty, Moscow State University

Pavel Yakutseni, Center for Advanced Studies, Saint-Petersburg State Polytechnical University

Yuri Yevdokimov, Institute of Molecular Biology of the RAS

Georgiy Zegrya, Nanotechnology Centre for Biology and Medicine, Ioffe Physico-Technical Institute of RAS
Topics Artificial Nanostructures Self-organized Nanostructures Nanoscale Organization of Biological Systems Nanocarbon Energy Nanomaterials Systems Biology Synthetic Biology Nanobionics Molecular Design Intellectual Data Analysis Nanomechanics and Nanohydrodynamics Diagnostics and Nanobiosensors Bio and Medical Applications Nanobiotech Risks Assessment for Human Health and Environment Nanobiotech Education and Industrial Innovation Far Future Challenges Official Language: English
<Node id="4339"/>http://www.spbcas.ru/…_Program.pdfКонференция<Node id="4384"/> соберет ведущих ученых, представителей промышленности, государственных учреждений и предоставит международный форум для обмена информацией и опытом в области нанобиотехнологий. И всё это — здОрово! Пожелаем им успехов и новых открытий!..</TextWithNodes>
<!-- The default annotation set -->

<AnnotationSet>
</AnnotationSet>

<!-- Named annotation set -->

<AnnotationSet Name="Key">
<Annotation Id="0" Type="связи_с_другими_организациями" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="1" Type="связи_с_другими_организациями" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="2" Type="связи_с_другими_организациями" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="3" Type="Период_времени" StartNode="200" EndNode="218">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="4" Type="связи_с_другими_организациями" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="5" Type="Url" StartNode="349" EndNode="397">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="6" Type="связи_с_другими_организациями" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="7" Type="Персона" StartNode="159" EndNode="169">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">Фамилия</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">Политехнич</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="8" Type="связи_с_другими_организациями" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="9" Type="связи_с_другими_организациями" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="10" Type="Деньги" StartNode="318" EndNode="333">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="11" Type="связи_с_другими_организациями" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="12" Type="связи_с_другими_организациями" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="13" Type="Url" StartNode="4339" EndNode="4384">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="14" Type="связи_с_другими_организациями" StartNode="0" EndNode="0">
</Annotation>
</AnnotationSet>

</GateDocument>
