<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<GateDocument>
<!-- The document's features-->

<GateDocumentFeatures>
</GateDocumentFeatures>
<!-- The document content area with serialized nodes -->

<TextWithNodes>Smart NanoBatteries make for efficient energy management
mPhase Technologies, Inc. is a U.S. based microfluidic and nanotechnology specialist. Through its wholly owned subsidiary Always Ready Inc., mPhase is commercializing its first nanotechnology product the Smart NanoBattery.

The Smart NanoBattery offers novel functionality not usually seen in a battery namely a shelf life of years, the ability to manage power in new ways, and a more environmentally friendly disposal option. This solution and other innovations from the field of nanotechnology will be presented to the interested specialist public at the sixth NanoEurope, which will be held in St.Gallen (Switzerland) on September 16 – 17, 2008.

One of the most important components restricting the performance and maintenance of wireless sensor systems is the battery required for powering the sensors. mPhase/AlwaysReady, a company headquartered in the U.S. State of New Jersey, is commercializing scientific findings from the field of microfluidics and nanotechnology. mPhase/AlwaysReady has developed a novel battery geared for sensor systems which will boost innovation initially in defense applications and later on also in commercial uses.
A smart battery based on a unique architecture
The nanobattery developed by mPhase/AlwaysReady utilizes knowledge from nanotechnology and microfluidics. It makes use of a unique membrane whose nanostructured surface is extremely water-repellent. This enables a liquid electrolyte to be kept separate from the battery’s electrode until energy is required. This allows the battery to be stored for an unlimited period of time before being used.

In addition, the battery is equipped with cells which can be individually activated for only those moments in which energy is needed. This is not possible in conventional batteries, where the chemical reaction cannot be interrupted until the battery has been entirely depleted. This energy on demand property gives the nanobattery a long useful life and makes it the ideal choice for wireless light-current sensor systems.
Broad range of battery applications is conceivable
The Smart NanoBattery opens up new possibilities in the areas of energy storage and management. Initial concrete applications satisfy defense requirements. In the future, this technology may also be integrated in portable electronic devices.
Smart surfaces enable other applications
The unique nanostructured membrane can also be designed to function as a smart surface that can filter liquids. This ability opens up the potential to use the membrane design for applications such as water purification and desalination, as well as self-cleaning glass.
About mPhase/AlwaysReady, Inc.
mPhase Technologies, Inc. is a U.S. based microfluidic and nanotechnology specialist. Through its wholly owned subsidiary AlwaysReady, Inc., mPhase is focused on developing and commercializing its first nanotechnology based product. This new battery technology is based on a well-patented phenomenon known as electrowetting, which provides a unique way to store energy and manage power that will revolutionize the battery industry. For more information please visit our website at <Node id="3190"/>www.mPhaseTech.com.<Node id="3209"/>

Safe Harbor Statement

This news release contains forward-looking statements related to future growth and earnings opportunities. Such statements are based upon certain assumptions and assessments made by management of companies mentioned in this press release in light of current conditions, expected future developments and other factors they believe to be appropriate. Actual results may differ as a result of factors over which the company has no control.

mPhase Contact:
 Mr. Gerard Adams mPhase Technologies, Inc. Investor Relations 973–256–3737 x105 Gerard@
<Node id="3777"/>mPhaseTech.com<Node id="3791"/> NanoEurope: Platform for innovations in nanotechnology
At the Nano-based Electronic and Sensor Systems conference to be held in St.Gallen on September 17, 2008, Fred Allen, President and CEO of AlwaysReady, will present the nanobattery to the interested specialist public. This specialist conference is part of the sixth NanoEurope, the European specialist congress with exhibition for technology and know-how transfer in nanotechnology.
Conference brochure now available
The detailed programs of the individual NanoEurope specialist conferences are now available online. The complete brochure can also be ordered as a printed version from the exhibition management. Booths at the NanoEurope 2008 can be booked up to June 13, 2008. Documentation for exhibitors is available at <Node id="4569"/>www.nanoeurope.com.<Node id="4588"/>
At a glance: NanoEurope 2008 Date: September 16 17, 2008 Venue: Olma Messen St.Gallen, St.Gallen (Switzerland) Exhibition: Hall 9.1; Congress: Halls 9.1.2, 9.2, and 2.1 Registration: By online ticketing at <Node id="4795"/>www.nanoeurope.ch<Node id="4812"/> 
Following the successful event in the past year with some 3,500 visitors from over 40 countries, the NanoEurope is once again available this year as a meeting platform for the interested specialist public. The event in 2008 offers entrepreneurs and managers from industry and research institutes a forum for discussing commercialization strategies and acquiring investment know-how. In addition, the attendees can learn more about the following focal areas: Multifunctional Textiles, Nanobased Electronic and Sensor Systems, and Systems with Functionalized Surfaces and Structures. And for the fourth time this year, the internationally renowned NanoRegulation Conference on voluntary measures in Nano Risk Governance including an international Nano Stakeholder Dialog will be held as part of the NanoEurope 2008.
For more information, please contact: Nicole Friedli, NanoEurope Exhibition Manager Phone +41 (0)71 242 04 47 Fax +41 (0)71 242 02 32 Email nicole.friedli@
<Node id="5784"/>nanoeurope.com<Node id="5798"/> Dr. Jörg Güttinger, General Manager Nano-Cluster Bodensee (Co-organizer) Phone +41 (0)71 274 73 84 Email joerg.guettinger@
ncb.ch 
This media release is available under the following link: www.medieninformation.ch/mPhase</TextWithNodes>
<!-- The default annotation set -->

<AnnotationSet>
</AnnotationSet>

<!-- Named annotation set -->

<AnnotationSet Name="Key">
<Annotation Id="0" Type="Url" StartNode="3777" EndNode="3791">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="1" Type="Url" StartNode="5784" EndNode="5798">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="2" Type="Url" StartNode="3190" EndNode="3209">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="3" Type="Url" StartNode="4569" EndNode="4588">
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="4" Type="Url" StartNode="4795" EndNode="4812">
</Annotation>
</AnnotationSet>

</GateDocument>
